{"tossups": [{"question": "<b><u>The Peace Tower was built to commemorate the birth of this figure, but the</u></b> <b><u>U.S. forced its partial removal due to the presence of the Imperial slogan \"Eight World</u></b> <b><u>Regions Under One Roof.\" One theory claims this figure was actually an alchemist</u></b> <b><u>named Xu Fu [[SHOO FOO]], who served (+)</u> Qin Shi Huang Di and travelled eastward during one region's Yayoi period. The three-legged crow </b><em><b>Yata-Garasu</b></em><b> led this mythical figure to the land of Yamato, where his forces defeated the Emishi people to dominate the island of (*) </b>Honshu. The first mythical emperor of Japan was, for the points, which direct descendant of Amaterasu?", "answer": "Emperor <b><u>Jimmu</u></b> (or <b><u>Jimmu</u></b>-tenno)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>In a majority opinion, this Justice dealt with an establishment owned by</u></b> <b><u>Moreton Rolleston and upheld the constitutionality of enforcing Title II of the Civil</u></b> <b><u>Rights Act against the Heart of Atlanta Motel. In another majority opinion, this man</u></b> <b><u>noted that many states rejected a certain \u201cignoble shortcut\u201d in (+)</u> </b><em><b>Wolf v. Colorado</b></em><b>. That 1961 case subjected the states to the exclusionary rule, setting limitations on what evidence was admissible under the Fourth (*) </b>Amendment. For the points, name this Supreme Court Justice who authored the opinion in <em>Mapp v. Ohio</em>.", "answer": "Tom C(ampbell) <b><u>Clark</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>One ruler of this name defeated Azariah of Judah and subjugated Qedar. The</u></b> <b><u>first king of this name recorded a number of his military campaigns on a set of \u201cfifth</u></b> <b><u>year annals\u201d that took the form of eight-sided prisms. The third king of this name</u></b> <b><u>appointed eunuchs as governors (+)</u> and decreased the size of individual provinces in order to weaken subordinates. The Neo-Hittites were defeated by that king of this name, who was said to have ruled the \u201cFour Corners of the World\u201d before being succeeded by his son, (*) </b>Shalmaneser V. For the points, give this name shared by various Assyrian kings.", "answer": "<b><u>Tiglath-Pileser</u></b> (accept <b><u>Tukult\u012b-apil-E\u0161arra</u></b> I; accept <b><u>Tukult\u012b-apil-E\u0161arra</u></b> III; accept <b><u>Tiglath-Pileser</u></b> I; accept <b><u>Tiglath-Pileser</u></b> III)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b><u>One act committed by this group is widely credited for the discontinuation</u></b> <b><u>and high resale value of Nike Decade sneakers. This group purchased a home in</u></b> <b><u>Rancho Santa Fe, California that they renamed \"The Mission.\" In their most famous</u></b> <b><u>act, members of this group washed (+)</u> phenobarbital mixed with apple sauce down with vodka and secured (*) </b>plastic bags around their heads. For the points, name this UFO cult founded by Bonnie Nettles and Marshal Appelwhite which had 37 members commit suicide in 1997 with the approach of the Hale-Bopp comet.", "answer": "<b><u>Heaven's Gate</u></b> (accept <b><u>Human Individual Metamorphosis</u></b>; accept <b><u>Total</u></b> <b><u>Overcomers Anonymous</u></b>)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "<b><u>An enslaved member of this organization known as Cato helped foil an</u></b> <b><u>attempted kidnapping of New Jersey governor William Livingston. Anna Strong is</u></b> <b><u>believed by some to have been this organization's \"Agent 355.\" Other members of this</u></b> <b><u>organization included Major Benjamin (+)</u> Talmadge and tailor Hercules Mulligan. This organization was named by George Washington after a county in Virginia, and it discovered that (*) </b>Benedict Arnold was plotting with John Andr\u00e9 to turn over West Point to the British. For the points, name this ring of spies in and around New York City during the American Revolution.", "answer": "<b><u>Culper</u></b> Ring", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Kevin Cunningham noted the use of \u201ccattle trucks and trains\u201d during this</u></b> <b><u>campaign, one portion of which was officially referred to as a \u201cliquidation.\u201d One</u></b> <b><u>justification offered for this event was that, if it did not occur, \u201cthe capitalist [would]</u></b> <b><u>inevitably return.\u201d Banners used during this event referred to the (+)</u> central group as the \u201cwreckers of agriculture.\u201d Taking place during the First Five Year Plan, this event resulted in the deportation of nearly two million members of (*) </b>one class. For the points, name this Soviet campaign targeting a namesake group of wealthy peasants.", "answer": "<b><u>Dekulakization</u></b> (or <b><u>Rozkurkulennia</u></b>; accept answers indicating <b><u>repression</u></b> of the <b><u>kulak</u></b>s; prompt on \"Collectivization\")", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>In response to this event, Police Commissioner Arthur Woods said that it</u></b> <b><u>taught America that it \u201cmust not again be caught napping.\u201d Frank Hague claimed that</u></b> <b><u>one vehicle involved in this event was \u201ctied up\u2026 to avoid a twenty-five dollar charge.\"</u></b> <b><u>A clock tower owned by the</u> </b><em><b><u>Jersey Journal</u></b></em><b><u> (+)</u> was affected by this event, in which the </b><em><b>Johnson Barge No. 17</b></em><b>\u2019s 100,000-pound store of TNT was set off. Four people died in this event during which the (*) </b>Statue of Liberty was damaged. For the points, name this 1916 event in which German agents sabotaged an American munitions shipment intended for World War One troops.", "answer": "<b><u>Black Tom</u></b> Explosion (accept <b><u>Black Tom</u></b> incident or clear-knowledge equivalents)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>In 1865, this city experienced riots over the imprisonment of a woman who</u></b> <b><u>purportedly stole two pounds of beef drippings. A 1936 march of fascists led by</u></b> <b><u>Oswald Mosley in this city's Leylands neighborhood led to the Battle of Holbeck (+)</u></b> <b>Moor. Parliamentary forces under the command of Thomas Fairfax took control of this city from the Royalists who were led by William Saville (*) </b>in 1642. For the points, name this city in West Yorkshire, a historical center of the British wool trade.", "answer": "<b><u>Leeds</u></b> (accept <b><u>Leeds</u></b> Dripping Riot)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Buddhism spread in this kingdom in the Sabi Period, during which the capital</u></b> <b><u>was moved from an isolated mountainous region. Malgal were said to have fought</u></b> <b><u>with a ruler of this kingdom named Daru, whose generosity is detailed in the</u> </b><em><b><u>Samguk</u></b></em> <em><b><u>Sagi</u></b></em><b><u>. (+)</u> Onjo founded this kingdom, which bordered Gaya to its east. This kingdom was closely allied with Kofun-era Japan, leading to the introduction of the Chinese writing system. The Tang (*) </b>Dynasty\u2019s defeat of this dynasty led to its subjugation by Silla. For the points, the Three Kingdoms of Korea included Silla, Goguryeo, and what other kingdom?", "answer": "<b><u>Baekje</u></b> (or <b><u>Paekche</u></b>; accept <b><u>Nambuyeo</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>The Society for Promoting Manual Labor in Literary Institutions was created</u></b> <b><u>to employ this man, who, as head of the Lane Rebels, is thought to have led the first</u></b> <b><u>student movement in the United States. This man was regarded as being \u201cas eloquent</u></b> <b><u>as an angel, and as powerful as thunder\u201d by Lyman (+)</u> Beecher, whose daughter Harriet\u2019s novel </b><em><b>Uncle Tom\u2019s Cabin</b></em><b> advocated a similar cause to that of this man\u2019s best-known work. That work by this man was written with the assistance of the Grimk\u00e9 (*) </b>sisters, one of whom he married. For the points, name this early abolitionist who authored <em>American Slavery as It Is</em>.", "answer": "Theodore Dwight <b><u>Weld</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>At the behest of Thomas Jefferson, this man came to Washington and relayed</u></b> <b><u>in-depth information about the state of New Spain, even delineating the borders of</u></b> <b><u>the newly acquired Louisiana Purchase. With assistance from this man, Joseph Louis</u></b> <b><u>Gay-Lussac discovered that the (+)</u> water molecule is one part oxygen and two parts hydrogen. The Peru Current was originally named for this European polymath, who recorded its cool temperatures in his work </b><em><b>Kosmos</b></em><b>. (*) </b>For the points, name this Prussian explorer and naturalist who was an early proponent of human-caused climate change.", "answer": "Alexander von <b><u>Humboldt</u></b> (or Friedrich Wilhelm Heinrich Alexander von <b><u>Humboldt</u></b>; accept <b><u>Humboldt</u></b> Current)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Reporter Igor Vukic [[VOO-kitch]] intentionally downplayed atrocities</u></b> <b><u>committed by this organization at Jasenovac [[yah-see-NOH-vahts]] by claiming they</u></b> <b><u>\"played football and had concerts.\" Ante Paveli\u0107 [[PAH-veh-lich]],</u> </b><em><b><u>Poglavnik</u></b></em><b><u> of this</u></b> <b><u>organization, ordered his underlings to commit the (+)</u> assassination of Alexander I of Yugoslavia. Along with the Nazi party, the Bigelow Report outed the Roman Catholic church for hiding this (*) </b>organization's gold. For the points, name this fascist Croatian paramilitary that formed an Axis puppet state during the Second World War.", "answer": "<b><u>Usta\u0161e</u></b> [[ooh-STAH-sheh]] (or <b><u>Ustasha</u></b>; accept <b><u>Croatia</u></b>n <b><u>Revolutionary</u> </b>Movement or <b><u>Hrvatski revolucionarni</u></b> pokret before \"Croatia\" is mentioned; accept <b><u>Usta\u0161e</u></b> vojnica)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>A monument at this battle site commemorates a one-time owner of the</u></b> <em><b><u>Chicago Tribune</u></b></em><b><u>, Colonel Robert McCormick. French Schneider tanks took German</u></b> <b><u>machine gun positions in this battle, during which Theodore Roosevelt, Jr. (+)</u></b> <b>reinforced American lines. The impact of this battle was overshadowed by the Allied victory at the Third Battle of the Aisne [[AYN]] (*) </b>one week later. For the points, name this 1918 battle in France, the first major battle of World War One in which the United States participated.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Cantigny</u></b> [[kahn-teen-YEE]]", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Local peasants defeated a wing of this force on Wind Hill, killing the Frisian</u></b> <b><u>Duke Ubba. This force, which used the Isle of Thanet as a staging ground for an</u></b> <b><u>invasion, captured the East Anglian king, Saint Edmund, and beheaded him for</u></b> <b><u>refusing to renounce (+)</u> Christianity. The successor to this army, led by the noble Guthrum, lost at Edington to Alfred the Great, leading to the containment of the Norse and establishment of the Danelaw. (*) </b>Halfdan Ragnarsson, Ivar the Boneless, and Bj\u00f6rn Ironside were leaders of, for the points, what coalition force of Vikings who invaded England in the 9th century?", "answer": "<b><u>Great Heathen</u></b> Army (accept <b><u>Viking Great</u></b> Army before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Due to an oath this man swore to his wife, Dugu, this emperor purportedly</u></b> <b><u>refused to keep concubines throughout his reign. This ruler ordered the construction</u></b> <b><u>of the Renshou Palace away from his capital at Chang\u2019an. The Northern and Southern</u></b> <b><u>Dynasties Period was brought to an (+)</u> end by this emperor, who reunified China in 589 AD. A series of locks were built on a project begun under this emperor that ultimately connected the Yellow and (*) </b>Yangtze Rivers. For the points, name this founder of the Sui dynasty who began construction of the Grand Canal.", "answer": "Emperor <b><u>Wen</u></b> of Sui (accept <b><u>Yang Jian</u></b>; accept <b><u>Puliuru Jian</u></b>; accept <b><u>Narayana</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This woman was arrested after the publication of a poster in which she</u></b> <b><u>demanded the public choose between the \"Three Urns,\" which included a unitary</u></b> <b><u>republic, federation, or constitutional monarchy. This member of the Society of the</u></b> <b><u>Friends of Truth suggested that, since women had \"the right to mount the scaffold,\"</u></b> <b><u>they too must have the (+)</u> \"right to mount the speaker's platform.\" This ally of the Girondins wrote a reply to a document drafted by the Marquis (*) </b>de Lafayette. For the points, name this French playwright and author of the <em>Declaration of the Rights of Woman</em> <em>and of the Female Citizen</em>.", "answer": "Olympe de <b><u>Gouges</u></b> (or Marie <b><u>Gouze</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Description acceptable. During this specific historical period, the</u> </b><em><b><u>Ee-ja-nai-ka</u> </b></em><b><u>festivities, which resembled the European dancing plague, reached its greatest</u></b> <b><u>popularity. During this period, the killing of the namesake English merchant in the</u></b> <b><u>Richardson Affair led to the UK's bombing of (+)</u> Kagushima in the Satsuma region. The ending of the isolationist policy of </b><em><b>sakoku</b></em><b> by Shogun Iesada occurred at the beginning of this historical period. Commodore (*) </b>Matthew Perry's opening of Japanese ports began, for the points, what historical period of Japanese history, the end of the Tokugawa Shogunate prior to the rise of Emperor Meiji?", "answer": "<b><u>Bakumatsu</u></b> (accept more specific answers like the <b><u>Boshin</u></b> War; accept descriptions like the <b><u>End of the Edo Period</u></b> or <b><u>End of the Tokugawa</u></b> Shogunate before mentioned; prompt on \"Edo Period\" or \"Tokugawa Shogunate\" alone; do not accept \"Meiji Restoration\")", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Insurrectionists in this war hired the USS</u> </b><em><b><u>Virginius</u></b></em><b><u> to run troops through a</u></b> <b><u>blockade, only to be captured by the corvette</u> </b><em><b><u>Tornado</u></b></em><b><u>. Teenage poet Jos\u00e9 Mart\u00ed was</u></b> <b><u>arrested during this conflict and deported to Spain. Negotiated in Camag\u00fcey [[kah-</u><u>mah-HWEH]], the Pact of (+)</u> Zanjon [[zahn-HOHN]] ended this conflict and promised the emancipation of slaves in a Caribbean colony by the late 1880s. (*) </b>Cuba failed to achieve independence during, for the points, what lengthy war of the 1860s and 1870s which ended with Spain reasserting control over the island?", "answer": "<b><u>Ten Years'</u></b> War (accept Guerra de los <b><u>Diez A\u00f1os</u></b>; accept <b><u>War of '68</u></b>; prompt on \"Guerra Grande\"; do not accept \"Cuban War of Independence\")", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Rohtas gained prominence due to changes made to this structure under a</u></b> <b><u>ruler who ordered the regular spacing of</u> </b><em><b><u>baolis</u></b></em><b><u>. Megasthenes noted that members of</u></b> <b><u>one army maintained this structure, and several renovations were made to this</u></b> <b><u>pathway under the namesake founder of the (+)</u> Suri Dynasty. This network was described as \u201ca river of life as nowhere else exists in the world\" by Rudyard Kipling, who described the solitude of a \u201cfifteen hundred mile\u201d section. Passing through (*) </b>Peshawar, Chittagong, and Kolkata, for the points, what was this ancient highway of the Indian subcontinent?", "answer": "<b><u>Grand Trunk</u></b> Road (accept <b><u>Uttara</u></b>path; accept Sarak-e-<b><u>Azam</u></b>; accept <b><u>Badshahi</u> </b>Sarak; accept Sarak-e-<b><u>Sher Shah</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>A woman named Jessie, who was the wife of one person killed in this event,</u></b> <b><u>married one of its perpetrators twelve days later. An exchange during this event was</u></b> <b><u>prompted when a warrant was deemed \u201cbogus\u201d by Cabell Testerman. Centered near</u></b> <b><u>the Pocahontas (+)</u> District, this event was the subject of a 1987 film by John Sayles. Members of the Baldwin-Felts Agency participated in this event, in the aftermath of which Sid Hatfield was assassinated. The fallout from this event led to the next year's (*) </b>Battle of Blair Mountain. For the points, name this 1920 shootout involving coal miners in West Virginia.", "answer": "<b><u>Matewan</u></b> Massacre (or Battle of <b><u>Matewan</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>The first mass movement of these people in the mid-13th century may have</u></b> <b><u>been incited by Joachim [[ZHOH-ah-keem]] of Fiore in the city of Perugia. This</u></b> <b><u>movement, sometimes known as the</u> </b><em><b><u>laudesi</u></b></em><b><u> for their constant chanting, was officially</u></b> <b><u>condemned in a papal bull by Clement VI. (+)</u> This movement, which lived on in the New World as the \"Penitent Brothers,\" aimed to escape the \"Dance of Death\" by doing an action (*) </b>for which this group is named. For the points, name this mass movement, popular during the Black Death in Europe, in which adherents whipped themselves and others as an act of repentance.", "answer": "<b><u>Flagellant</u></b>s (accept <b><u>Flagellant</u></b>ism; or <em><b><u>Laudesi</u></b></em>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>In a work about this event, Olga Palagia [[pah-LAH-gyah]] noted how the</u></b> <b><u>\u201cthrow of dice\u201d could sometimes determine outcomes. According to myth, a son of</u></b> <b><u>Minos named Androgeus [[an-DROH-gee-us]] was killed by jealous rivals after his</u></b> <b><u>success at one of these events. Amphorae (+)</u> were given as prizes at these non-Olympic events. Like similar events it featured the </b><em><b>diaulos</b></em><b> sprint, and its revival was credited to (*) </b>Peisistratos. This non-Panhellenic event began with offerings to Poseidon as well as to its city\u2019s namesake goddess of wisdom. For the points, name this sporting event in a major Greek-city state.", "answer": "<b><u>Panathenaic</u></b> Games (or <b><u>Panathenaia</u></b>; prompt on \u201cAthenian Games\u201d or \u201cAthenian sporting event\u201d or similar answers)", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "<b><u>While imprisoned, this man learned of the disappearance of his son, Juan,</u></b> <b><u>aboard</u> </b><em><b><u>La Concepci\u00f3n</u></b></em><b><u>. This man's recommendations to Phillip II ultimately led to the</u></b> <b><u>creation of the Spanish Treasure Fleet. Jean Ribault was a rival of this man, who was</u></b> <b><u>tasked with eliminating the French presence around (+)</u> Fort Caroline. One settlement led by this man was located along the Matanzas River and was established in 1565, making it the oldest continuously inhabited settlement in the (*) </b>continental U.S. For the points, name this Spanish adventurer who governed St. Augustine.", "answer": "Pedro <b><u>Men\u00e9ndez</u></b> de <b><u>Avil\u00e9s</u></b> (accept either underlined portion)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>During this event, Rufus Spalding had the name of John McLean withdrawn,</u></b> <b><u>and this event was preceded by a similar event focusing on a \u201cNorth American\u201d body.</u></b> <b><u>Cassius Clay received three informal votes during this event, which involved a</u></b> <b><u>selection of New Jersey senator William L. Dayton. (+)</u> This was the first event of its kind and selected a California senator nicknamed the \u201cPathfinder.\u201d John C. Fr\u00e9mont was nominated during this convention before losing the (*) </b>general election to the only bachelor president. For the points, name this convention held four years prior to one that nominated Abraham Lincoln.", "answer": "<b><u>Republican Nominating</u></b> Convention of <b><u>1856</u></b> (or <b><u>1856 RNC</u></b>; or <b><u>Republican</u></b> <b><u>National</u></b> Convention of <b><u>1856</u></b>; accept <b><u>First Republican Nominating</u></b> Convention, <b><u>First</u></b> <b><u>RNC</u></b>; or <b><u>First Republican National</u></b> Convention before \u201cfirst\u201d is mentioned; prompt on partial answers; prompt on Presidential \u201cElection of 1856\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>It has been theorized that this man's delusions may have been caused by</u></b> <b><u>consumption of the plant</u> </b><em><b><u>iboga</u></b></em><b><u>, causing his banning of the word \"intellectual\" as well</u></b> <b><u>as all literary output. This man's soldiers, allegedly dressed as Santa Claus, executed</u></b> <b><u>prisoners in a football stadium while (+)</u> \"Those Were the Days\" played over loud speakers. The year before his execution, this dictator changed his country's motto to \"There is no other God than [this man]\" while he changed the name of the island of Fernando Po to (*) </b>his own name. For the points, name this 20th century dictator of Equatorial Guinea.", "answer": "Francisco Mac\u00edas <b><u>Nguema</u></b> [[nah-GWEH-mah]] (accept <b><u>Mac\u00edas</u></b>; accept either underlined portion of <b><u>Masie</u><u>Nguema</u></b> Biyogo \u00d1egue Ndong)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This coach once conducted an interview with Manfred Rommel as part of a</u></b> <b><u>broadcast series in which he delivered historical perspectives on war films. A eulogy</u></b> <b><u>for this coach was delivered by Richard Nixon, who lamented that this man only</u></b> <b><u>wanted to talk about \"foreign policy\" rather than football. Bo (+)</u> Schembechler of Michigan was a rival to this man, who was dismissed from one team after punching Clemson nose-tackle Charlie Bauman during the 1978 Gator Bowl. Serving as head coach at a Big Ten (*) </b>school from 1951 to 1978, for the points, who was this longtime coach of the Ohio State Buckeyes?", "answer": "Woody <b><u>Hayes</u></b> (or Wayne Woodrow <b><u>Hayes</u></b>)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "<b><u>In May 2021, this politician accused the Interior Ministry of harassing her</u></b> <b><u>relatives and political allies ahead of parliamentary elections. In November of that</u></b> <b><u>same year, it was revealed that this politician was followed and wiretapped over</u></b> <b><u>suspicions of her involvement in overthrowing (+)</u> Prime Minister Pavel Filip. This politician posted a video on YouTube concerning her plan to establish a new political party, the Party of Action and (*) </b>Solidarity. For the points, name this pro-European politician, the first and only female president of Moldova.", "answer": "Maia <b><u>Sandu</u></b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man was depicted in a cage on top of two griffins \"conquering the air\" in a</u></b> <b><u>painting from Burgundian chronicler Jean Wauquelin's biography of him. In a</u></b> <b><u>Flemish painting, this man is depicted being lowered into the sea in a bathysphere</u></b> <b><u>and being paid homage by fish, referencing a scene from his namesake (+)</u> </b><em><b>Romance</b></em><b>. In Islamic depictions, this man is referred to as the \"two-horned one,\" and he is often depicted in Greek sculptures with a (*) </b>lion on his helmet. Seen battling Darius III in a mosaic from Pompeii, for the points, who was this culturally influential Macedonian conqueror?", "answer": "<b><u>Alexander the Great</u></b> (or <b><u>Alexander III</u></b> of Macedon; accept <em><b><u>Alexander</u></b> Romance</em>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b><u>One side in this battle set up a barricade at Cliveden, which was stormed by</u></b> <b><u>John Laurens's soldiers. Nathanael Greene\u2019s troops mistakenly opened fire on</u></b> <b><u>Anthony Wayne during a withdrawal from this battle. Heavy fog characterized this</u></b> <b><u>battle, which was a victory for William (+)</u> Howe two weeks after the Battle of Paoli Tavern. Roughly a month after Brandywine, and despite a loss at this battle, (*) </b>George Washington\u2019s troops were able to set up camp in Valley Forge. For the points, name this 1777 battle fought in a namesake town, which was at the time northwest of Philadelphia.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Germantown</u></b> (Editor's Note: Germantown was incorporated into Philadelphia in 1854.)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Following the execution of this man and his brother, Sir John Maxwell</u></b> <b><u>suppressed two poems from this man and advised Prime Minister H. H. Asquith not to</u></b> <b><u>return the bodies of this man and his brother to their family. This political activist</u></b> <b><u>wrote several allegorical plays in the Irish language including (+)</u> </b><em><b>The King</b></em><b> and </b><em><b>The </b><b>Singer</b></em><b>. Sworn into the Irish Republican Brotherhood by Bulmer Hobson, (*) </b>for the points, who was this Irish nationalist and revolutionary who issued the orders to all volunteer units during the Easter Rising of 1916, becoming a symbol of Irish independence?", "answer": "Patrick Henry <b><u>Pearse</u></b> (accept <b><u>P\u00e1draig</u></b>; accept either underlined portion of <b><u>P\u00e1draic</u><u>Pearse</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Jewish-American sculptor Moses Jacob Ezekiel is considered vital to this</u></b> <b><u>viewpoint by historians like Gabriel Reich due to his creation of works like</u> </b><em><b><u>John W.</u></b></em> <em><b><u>Daniel</u></b></em><b><u> and</u> </b><em><b><u>Virginia Mourning Her Dead</u></b></em><b><u>. The intervention of UDC President-General</u></b> <b><u>Mildred Rutherford led to this narrative being (+)</u> codified in turn-of-the-century history textbooks. Alexander Stephens's contemporary \"Cornerstone Speech\" is often cited by modern historians when (*) </b>dismissing this viewpoint as revisionist. For the points, name this pseudo-historical denialist ideology which rejects the idea that slavery was a cause of the Civil War in favor of a \u201cheroic\u201d Confederacy.", "answer": "<b><u>Lost Cause</u></b> of the Confederacy (prompt on descriptions like \"pro-Confederacy\", \"pro-Southern\", or \"slavery denialist\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>The incident that killed this man near Point Barrow also claimed the life of his</u></b> <b><u>friend, comedian Will Rogers. Berlin and Novosibirsk were the sites of repairs for this</u></b> <b><u>man while he was attempting a notable feat alongside Harold Gatty, a (+)</u> voyage which took eight days. This man later repeated that same feat by himself in seven days by relying on an autopilot and a (*) </b>compass. The pilot of the <em>Winnie Mae</em> was, for the points, which American aviator, the first man to fly solo around the world?", "answer": "Wiley <b><u>Post</u></b> (or Wiley Hardeman <b><u>Post</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Bob Dylan supposedly drafted a song opposing this project that states, \"For</u></b> <b><u>twenty long years there's been a shadow hanging round / that any day the bulldozers</u></b> <b><u>will throw our houses down.\" Opponents of this transportation project sought the</u></b> <b><u>support of the leader of the \"Save the (+)</u> Village\" campaign, Jane Jacobs, after John Lindsay and Robert Moses threatened the neighborhoods of SoHo (*) </b>and Little Italy. For the points, name this cancelled portion of Interstate 78 between the Holland Tunnel and the Williamsburg Bridge in New York City.", "answer": "<b><u>Lower Manhattan Expressway</u></b> (or <b><u>LOMEX</u></b>; prompt on partial answer; prompt on <b><u>I</u></b>nterstate <b><u>78</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This astronomer wrote a critique of an earlier thinker whom this man</u></b> <b><u>credited with inventing the armillary sphere. Much of what is known about this</u></b> <b><u>author of</u> </b><em><b><u>Against the Geography of Eratosthenes</u></b></em><b><u> comes from commentaries on and</u></b> <b><u>accounts from Ptolemy\u2019s</u> </b><em><b><u>Almagest</u></b></em><b><u>. (+)</u> The first reliable method of predicting solar eclipses is credited to this man, who discovered the changing rotational axis of a certain body. Considered the father of (*) </b>trigonometry, for the points, who was this Ancient Greek astronomer from Nicaea thought to have discovered the procession of the equinoxes?", "answer": "<b><u>Hipparchus</u></b> of Nicaea", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "<b><u>The British government promoted the evangelical Clapham Sect to promote</u></b> <b><u>this view in an effort to allow the sugar production of the West Indies to compete with</u></b> <b><u>a rival state. In response to this event, plantation owners, known as</u> </b><em><b><u>fazendeiros</u></b></em><b><u>,</u></b> <b><u>started the organization \"Society for the (+)</u> Promotion of Immigration\" to acquire replacement labor. The Rio Branco Law preceded this event, of which an ailing Pedro II (*) </b>was informed while away in Milan for medical treatment. Princess Isabel of the House of Braganza championed, for the points, what action facilitated by the Golden Law?", "answer": "<b><u>Abolition</u></b> of Slavery in <b><u>Brazil</u></b> (accept word forms and descriptions such as \"getting rid of Slavery in Brazil\")", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>One subset of this political faction who had abandoned the \"Vanguard Party\"</u></b> <b><u>were labeled Liquidationists. The Constitutional Democrats and this political faction</u></b> <b><u>were both made illegal in 1921 following the Kronstadt Rebellion. Jewish-Russian</u></b> <b><u>economists associated with the Bund, including (+)</u> Boris Berlatsky, were targeted in one of Stalin's first \"Show Trials\" named for this political faction. Led by Julius Martov, (*) </b>a friend-turned-rival of Vladimir Lenin, for the points, what was this faction of moderate Communists whose name derived from the Russian for \"Minority,\" opposed to the Bolsheviks?", "answer": "<b><u>Menshevik</u></b>s (prompt on \"Minority\" before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This person was expelled from Norwich military school after herding sheep</u></b> <b><u>into the barracks. This man was promoted to captain in the same year in which he</u></b> <b><u>was given command of the USS</u> </b><em><b><u>Dolphin</u></b></em><b><u> upon its launch. During the Civil War, this</u></b> <b><u>man served with David Farragut (+)</u> as an executive lieutenant on the USS </b><em><b>Mississippi</b></em><b>. While aboard his flagship, the USS </b><em><b>Olympia</b></em><b>, this man gave the command, \u201cYou may (*) </b>fire when you are ready, Gridley.\" For the points, name this admiral who defeated the Spanish fleet in the Battle of Manila Bay.", "answer": "George <b><u>Dewey</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>During this war, the Scots Guards perpetrated the Batang Kali Massacre on</u></b> <b><u>unarmed villagers in the modern state of Selangor. The so-called \"New Villages\" were</u></b> <b><u>created during this conflict in an effort to intern ethnically Chinese dissidents, a part</u></b> <b><u>of the larger Briggs (+)</u> Plan supported by the Atlee government. This communist insurgency largely ended after the failure of the Baling Talks prompted MNLA leader Chin Peng to flee to nearby (*) </b>Thailand and retire. For the points, name this mid-20th century \"Emergency,\" a guerilla war fought against British rule.", "answer": "<b><u>Malaya</u></b>n Emergency (or Darurat <b><u>Malaya</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}], "bonuses": []}